the-diplomat.com 2019-05-02

# Privacy Policy | The Diplomat

_The Diplomat_ is fully committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy statement explains _The Diplomat’s_ data collection and use practices for the magazine. By accessing _The Diplomat_ , you are consenting to the information collection and use practices described in this privacy statement.

 **Personal Information**

_The Diplomat_ will ask you when necessary for personal information that can personally identify you (personal information) or that allows us to contact you to provide a service or carry out a transaction that you have requested such as requesting information about our magazine, entering a contest, subscribing to our newsletter, providing details for an event, submitting work to _The Diplomat_ or requesting information about the magazine. The personal information we collect may include your name, home address, country, school name, e-mail address, or phone number. _The Diplomat_ may collect certain information about your visit to our site, such as the name of the Internet service provider and the Internet Protocol (IP) address through which you access the Internet; the date and time you accessed _The Diplomat_ ; the pages that you access while at _The Diplomat_ and the Internet address of the Web site from which you linked directly to our site. This information is used to help improve our magazine, analyse site trends, and for administration of _The Diplomat_.

When posting comments to _The Diplomat_ , we urge you to be careful only to enter information on your profile that you are comfortable sharing with the public at large.Please keep in mind that if you disclose personal information through public online discussions on _The Diplomat_ , this information may be collected and used by others. We would recommend against giving out personal information to strangers online, which they may use for illegal or harmful purposes.

**Use of Your Personal Information**

The personal information collected on _The Diplomat_ will be used to operate the website and to provide the service(s) or carry out the request(s) you have requested or authorized.

In support of these uses, _The Diplomat_ may use personal information to provide you with more effective services, to improve the magazine and any related products or services, and to make _The Diplomat_ easier to use.

We may use your personal information to provide you with important information about the service that you are using, including updates and latest news. Additionally, with your permission, we may send you information about other _The Diplomat_ services, and/or share information with our partners so they may send you information about their services.

_The Diplomat_ occasionally hires other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as Web site hosting, delivering prizes, answering questions about services, and sending information about our magazine. We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

_The Diplomat_ may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on _The Diplomat_ ; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of _The Diplomat_ and our family of Web sites; or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of _The Diplomat_ employees or agents, users of _The Diplomat_ services, or members of the public.

Personal information collected on _The Diplomat_ may be stored and processed in Japan or any other country in which _The Diplomat_ or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using _The Diplomat_ , you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country.

**Control of Personal Information**

Except as otherwise described in this statement, personal information you provide on _The Diplomat_ will not be shared outside of _The Diplomat_ and its controlled affiliates without your permission.

Please be aware that this privacy statement and any choices you make on _The Diplomat_ will not necessarily apply to personal information you may have provided to _The Diplomat_ in the context of other, separately operated, _The Diplomat_ services.

**Access to Your Personal Information**

Customer information is collected by _The Diplomat_ team.

**Security of Your Personal Information**

_The Diplomat_ is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure.

**Cookies**

We use cookies on _The Diplomat_ to improve ease of use. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programmes or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are assigned to you, and can only be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the main purposes of cookies is to save you time. If you navigate within a site, for example, a cookie helps the site to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of delivering relevant content and makes site navigation easier. When you return to the web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually adjust your browser setting to decline cookies if you like. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of this or other web sites you visit.

**Changes to This Privacy Statement.**

We may occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also revise the ‘last updated’ date at the top of the privacy statement. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. Your continued use of the service constitutes your agreement to this privacy statement and any updates.

**Contact Information**

_The Diplomat_ welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement. If you believe that _The Diplomat_ has not adhered to this privacy statement, please contact us by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#fe97909891be8a969bd39a978e9291939f8ad09d9193) or via mail at the address provided below, and we will use reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy any problem.

The Diplomat  
701 Ebisu MF Bldg.  
4-6-1 Ebisu, Shibuya-ku,  
Tokyo 150-0013  
Japan
